Guide to the UE National Office Records Relating to District 11 and District 11 Locals, 1936-1994 UE.4.1.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
UE National Office Records Relating to District 11 and District 11 Locals
1936-1994
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America
UE.4.1.11
15 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
This series contains files on United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (UE) District 11 and its locals collected by the UE national office. Included are correspondence, publications, minutes, and news clippings regarding local strikes, events, and organizing efforts.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
District 11 of the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America (UE) was initially comprised of locals in the Chicago area. As the union grew and incorporated locals of the United Farm Equipment and Metal Workers in 1949, the district included locals in Illinois, Wisconsin, South Dakota and Minnesota. The locals that are still in existence are now part of the UE's Western Region. This series contains files on UE District 11 and its locals collected by the UE national office. Included are correspondence, publications, minutes, and news clippings regarding local strikes, events, and organizing efforts. Most of the correspondence is between UE national officers and district or local officers.
Previous Citation
UE National Office Records Relating to District 11 and District 11 Locals, 1936-1994, UE.4.1.11, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
This series has been arranged into two subseries. The first contains records pertaining to District 11. The other subseries contains records pertaining to specific locals within the district, and are further arranged numerically by local number into sections.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America in 1975, 1986, 1997, and 2001.
Related Material
UE District 11 Records, 1940s-1990s, UE.15.11, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
UE Local 1139 Records, 1960s-1980s, UE.16.1139, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
UE Local 1150 Records, 1940s-1980s, UE.16.1150, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
UE Local 1180 Records, 1980s, UE.16.1180, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions -- Illinois -- Chicago -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions -- Middle West -- History -- 20th century; Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- United States -- History; Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- Middle West -- History; Labor; Emspak, Julius; Matles, James J.; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America. District 11; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America; DeMaio, Ernest
- District 11, 1.
  - District 11 Constitutions, February 1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District 11 Constitutions, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - District 11 Constitutions, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - District 11 Constitutions, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - District 11 Constitutions, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - District 11 Constitutions, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - District 11 Constitutions, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - District 11 Constitutions, 1942-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - District 11 Constitutions and Bylaws, 1949-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - District 11 Officers Minutes, January 23, 1940-March 1, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - District 11 Officers List, November 1, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - District 11 Membership Resolutions, 1941-1947, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Membership Resolution Regarding Civil Service with May 4, 1941, Harry Wold Letter to UE, May 1941; 1.
    - Membership Resolution Regarding Military Personnel, January 5, 1946; 2.
    - Membership Resolution Regarding Veterans and Housing with January 9, 1946, Ernest DeMaio Letter to District 11 Locals, January 5, 1946; 3.
    - Membership Resolution Regarding Strike Fund, January 6, 1946; 4.
    - Membership Resolution Regarding Civil Rights, January 11, 1947; 5.
    - Membership Resolution Regarding Organization, n.d.; 6.
    - Membership Resolution Regarding District Office and Affiliation, 7.
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 31, 1937-June 25, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, March 29, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, June 28-December 14, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, March 28, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, June 17, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, September 26, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, December 12, 1942-March 15, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, June 14, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, September 27, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, December 6, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, March 13, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, June 1944 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 9, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, December 12, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, March 18, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, July 15, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 6, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, January 5, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, April 1946 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, July 1946 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, September 21, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, January 11, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, April 1947 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, June 21, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 4, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, January 31, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, April 3, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, June 26, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, September 25, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, January-April 12, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, June 25, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 1949 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, January 1950 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, April 22, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, July 1950 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 14, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, January 13, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, April 14, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, July 7, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 6, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, January 19, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, April 26, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, July 19, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 4, 1952-January 10, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, April 25, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, July 1953 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 19, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, April 24, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District 11 Membership Minutes, October 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - District 11 Minutes, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - District 11 Minutes, 1985-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - District 11 District Council Meetings, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - District 11 District Council Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - District 11 District Council Meetings, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - District 11 Council Meeting, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - District 11 Council Meeting, 1956-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1943-1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Janet Barish to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Finances, April 12, 1943; 1.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Organization at Stewart Warner, July 21, 1943; 2.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Political Action and Local 1139, October 24, 1945; 3.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Finances, July 1, 1946; 4.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Inter-union Rivalry and IUE, August 18, 1950; 5.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 189, December 11, 1951; 6.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Finances, March 6, 1952; 7.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Finances and International Harvester Council, July 25, 1952; 8.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Finances and International Harvester Council, September 26, 1952; 9.
    - Barish to DeMaio Regarding Strikes and Marathon Electric, March 18, 1954; 10.
    - Joseph Dermody to DeMaio Regarding Organization at Western Electric, October 9, 1945; 11.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Julius Emspak to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Congress of Soviet-American Friendship, October 19, 1942; 1.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, March 5, 1943; 2.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Military and Staff Members with Letter to Whom It May Concern, April 4, 1943; 3.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, May 10, 1943; 4.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, May 24, 1943; 5.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, May 31, 1943; 6.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, June 11, 1943; 7.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, June 30, 1943; 8.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, July 30, 1943; 9.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Organization at Stewart Warner, August 4, 1943; 10.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Staff Members, October 6, 1943; 11.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, September 22, 1943; 12.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, October 27, 1943; 13.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, November 5, 1943; 14.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Women and Wages, November 26, 1943; 15.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, December 17, 1943; 16.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, December 27, 1943; 17.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, January 24, 1944; 18.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and District 1, January 24, 1944; 19.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, February 4, 1944; 20.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, March 9, 1944; 21.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding UE Headquarters, March 17, 1944; 22.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, June 2, 1944; 23.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, June 20, 1944; 24.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Political Action, July 19, 1944; 25.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, July 17, 1944; 26.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Julius Emspak to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Finances, August 11, 1944; 1.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Contracts and Organization, August 11, 1944; 2.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, September 1, 1944; 3.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, October 5, 1944; 4.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, October 19, 1944; 5.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, November 2, 1944; 6.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, December 1, 1944; 7.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, December 22, 1944; 8.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, December 20, 1944; 9.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, December 20, 1944; 10.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, January 11, 1945; 11.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, February 2, 1945; 12.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, February 16, 1945; 13.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, March 8, 1945; 14.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1103 and War Labor Board, March 9, 1945; 15.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Organization at Sylvania in Bloomington, April 13, 1945; 16.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, May 9, 1945; 17.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, April 20, 1945; 18.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Radio, June 13, 1945; 19.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Dues and Veterans, June 12, 1945; 20.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Unemployment and Congress of Industrial Organizations, July 20, 1945; 21.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Negotiations, September 25, 1945; 22.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding PAC and Local 1139, November 7, 1945; 23.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, December 18, 1945; 24.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, January 18, 1946; 25.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1105 Strike at Westinghouse, March 27, 1946; 26.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding GE and Westinghouse Strikes, April 8, 1946; 27.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, July 3, 1946-December 13, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Julius Emspak to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Local 1121 and Per Capita, July 3, 1946; 1.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Westinghouse and GE Strikes, July 19, 1946; 2.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Amalgamation of Locals 1101 and 1135, July 26, 1946; 3.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1107 and Per Capita, October 9, 1946; 4.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Organization at Colonial, October 7, 1946; 5.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1107 and Per Capita, December 4, 1946; 6.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita, January 28, 1947; 7.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Strike at Pioneer Engineering and Electric Machinery Manufacturing, May 27, 1947; 8.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Radio Broadcasts, May 27, 1947; 9.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Stewards Conferences in Minneapolis and Chicago, December 15, 1947; 10.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Organization at Mechanical Handling Devices, December 23, 1947; 11.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Officers and Visit, January 2, 1948; 12.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1150 and Dues with December 22, 1947, Lee Lundguen Letter to Emspak, January 13, 1948; 13.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding American Jewish Labor Council, February 16, 1948; 14.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, April 9, 1948; 15.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, September 13, 1948; 16.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1149 Strike with October 1, 1948, Viola Davis Letter to Emspak, October 4, 1948; 17.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1149 Strike, October 20, 1948; 18.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1150 Strike, March 3, 1948; 19.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Belmont Strike, March 24, 1949; 20.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Hoover and Belmont Strike, June 7, 1949; 21.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, October 19, 1949; 22.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Locals 101F and 112F, November 28, 1949; 23.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, December 13, 1949; 24.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Julius Emspak to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Finances, December 19, 1949; 1.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Taft-Hartley Affidavits and Inter-union Rivalry, December 22, 1949; 2.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1131 Disbanding, January 13, 1950; 3.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 112F, January 20, 1950; 4.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 112F, February 24, 1950; 5.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, March 1, 1950; 6.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 101F, April 11, 1950; 7.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 101F, April 13, 1950; 8.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 101F, April 17, 1950; 9.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 1150, April 25, 1950; 10.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 108F and Per Capita, July 18, 1950; 11.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, October 18, 1950; 12.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita and Local 1114, November 3, 1950; 13.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, November 17, 1950; 14.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Local 1131 Disbanding, November 27, 1950; 15.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and International Harvester Conference Board, December 20, 1950; 16.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 1140, January 17, 1951; 17.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 1150, January 25, 1951; 18.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, February 26, 1941; 19.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, March 1, 1951; 20.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Political Action, March 12, 1951; 21.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Publicity, April 23, 1951; 22.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Publicity, April 27, 1951; 23.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita and Local 1140F, May 7, 1951; 24.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Julius Emspak to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Local 1151F and Per Capita, May 15, 1951; 1.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Political Action, May 16, 1951; 2.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita and Local 140F, September 11, 1951; 3.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita and Local 140F, November 29, 1951; 4.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, December 20, 1951; 5.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, January 11, 1952; 6.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances and the Weber Case with January 23, 1952, David Scribner Letter to Emspak, January 29, 1952; 7.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding National Labor Relations Board and Local 168F, February 19, 1952; 8.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, July 1, 1952; 9.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, July 9, 1952; 10.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding International Harvester Strike, September 23, 1952; 11.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding the Sentner Case, October 6, 1952; 12.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Organization in Chicago, October 14, 1952; 13.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita of Locals 1140 and 1145, January 15, 1953; 14.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Amalgamations of Locals 1119 and 1150, February 3, 1953; 15.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Finances, March 2, 1953; 16.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Amalgamations of Locals 1119 and 1150, April 2, 1953; 17.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding African-Americans, June 12, 1953; 18.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita and Suspensions, November 18, 1953; 19.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Civil Liberties Committee, February 8, 1954; 20.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita, February 24, 1954; 21.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Inter-union Rivalry, IUE, and UE at Schenectudy, April 29, 1954; 22.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Civil Liberties with September 11, 1954, Edwin Campbell Letter to UE, September 17, 1954; 23.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Inter-union Rivalry at Locals 139F and 1133, November 5, 1954; 24.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita and Local 1150, December 2, 1954; 1.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Publicity, December 13, 1954; 2.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding American Safety Razor Boycott, December 27, 1954; 3.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita and International Harvester Locals, April 13, 1955; 4.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Per Capita at Locals 101F and 107F, May 18, 1955; 5.
    - Emspak to DeMaio Regarding Disbandings, Inter-union Rivalry and United Auto Workers, September 9, 1955; 6.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1944-1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Michael Essin to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Local 1113 and Jailings, February 10, 1954; 1.
    - Albert Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding Chicago Visit, January 5, 1944; 2.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding National Political Education Conference with June 7, 1944, Sidney Hillman Letter to Fitzgerald, June 15, 1944; 3.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding Negotiations and Hugo Manufacturing, January 13, 1948; 4.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding Sunbeam Strike, June 7, 1949; 5.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding Chicago Visit, August 24, 1949; 6.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding Peoria Sub-district, February 1, 1950; 7.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding Factionalism and Local 1140, March 3, 1950; 8.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding Mid-west Conference, January 31, 1951; 9.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding Chicago Visit, March 23, 1953; 10.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding National Farmers Union, March 9, 1954; 11.
    - Fitzgerald to DeMaio Regarding National Officers Meeting, March 25, 1954; 12.
    - Sidney Gilbert to DeMaio Regarding Decca in Chicago and Dues, November 12, 1943; 13.
    - Eleanor Holden to DeMaio Regarding Political Action, December 10, 1943; 14.
    - Mary Karpa Regarding Shoe Workers, September 21, 1944; 15.
    - Selma Kaslick to DeMaio Regarding Joe Cetner's Death, July 10, 1946; 16.
    - Ray Klausner to DeMaio Regarding Officers Visit, January 21, 1948; 17.
    - Mel Krantzler to DeMaio Regarding Dues in Chicago, March 7, 1951; 18.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - James Matles to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Organization in Chicago, November 18, 1942; 1.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Organization at Flexible Shaft and Hurley Machine, November 28, 1942; 2.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding MESA and Federation of Westinghouse Independent Salaried Union Inter-union Rivalry, December 7, 1942; 3.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 1145, December 28, 1942; 4.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Productivity, December 30, 1942; 5.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Battery Industry Organization and United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry with List of Firms, December 31, 1942; 6.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, January 7, 1943; 7.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, January 22, 1943; 8.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, February 2, 1943; 9.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Finances, February 3, 1943; 10.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, February 3, 1943; 11.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, February 5, 1943; 12.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Finances and Local 1114, February 9, 1943; 13.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Organization at Greenlea Brothers, February 12, 1943; 14.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Organization in Milwaukee, February 15, 1943; 15.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding War Labor Board and Finances, February 15, 1943; 16.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members and Local 1145, February 25, 1943; 17.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding District 11 Organization, March 11, 1943; 18.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Finances, March 23, 1943; 19.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Chicago Visit, April 7, 1943; 20.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Organization, April 8, 1943; 21.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, Organization at RCA in Indianapolis, and Inter-union Rivalry with International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers and United Auto Workers, April 14, 1943; 22.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Organization, April 15, 1943; 23.
    - Matles to DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, April 27, 1943; 24.
  - District 11 Ernest DeMaio Incoming Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - James Matles to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Staff Members, May 5, 1943; 1.